Mary Le

A **UX/UI Designer** with a background in user research, UX design, and front-end development.

EXPERIENCE

UX Designer | Amplify

September 2018 - Present

Define user personas, map user journey, wireframe user flow in lo-fi mockups. Create high-fi prototypes for sales and marketing demos. User test over 20 sessions to gather feedback for design iterations.

Front-end Developer | Northwestern Polytechnic University

April 2016 - July 2017

Created web and print designs with Sketch, Photoshop, and Illustrator. Built design components with HTML and CSS. Redesigned an internal school admin portal.

Front-end Web Developer | Mobile Action

May 2015 - December 2015

Collaborated with product managers and engineers to design and develop a new user-centered dashboard with mobile responsiveness.

Front-end Developer | Achievers

April 2015 - July 2015

Created design mockups with HTML and CSS and built a responsive mobile survey application with Javascript and AngularJS. Collected and analyzed over 200 usability test results from 3 design iterations. Worked with designers to develop and launch a corporate website relaunch.

PROJECTS

Lead UX Designer | Mareana

January 2018 - May 2018

Designed an interactive pop-up tutorial to onboard users using data from contextual interview data. Defined user personas and created wireframes, 2 lo-fi mockups in Sketch, and a high-fi prototype in InVision.

UX Designer | Human-Computer Interaction Design: Safety Map

August 2017 - December 2017

Collaborated on a team of six to design a mobile safety map application based on user research findings from surveys, interviews, heuristic evaluations, and user testings. User tested three design iterations created from low-fi mockups and high-fi prototypes in Sketch and InVision.

EDUCATION

Cornell University | Masters in Information Science (Focus: HCI, User Experience)
Graduated May 2018

University of California, Irvine | Bachelor of Arts in International Studies, Sociology Graduated June 2011

ABOUT ME

https://www.maryle.me linkedin.com/in/maaaryle maaaryle@gmail.com

SKILLS & TOOLS

UX Research

Survey design Contextual interviews Heuristic evaluation Usability testing Wireframing Prototyping

Design Tools

Sketch Balsamiq InVision UXPin Adobe Photoshop Adobe XD

Development Tools

HTML, CSS (Sass, LESS) Javascript Unity 3D Drupal Wordpress